[
    {
        "question": "Martin, a hacker, aimed to crash a target system. For this purpose, he spoofed the source IP address with the target's IP address and sent many ICMP ECHO request packets to an IP broadcast network, causing all the hosts to respond to the received ICMP ECHO requests and ultimately crashing the target machine. Identify the type of attack performed by Martin in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "UDP flood attack",
            "Multi vector attack",
            "Smurf attack",
            "Fragmentation attack"
        ],
        "answer": "Smurf attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Williams, a professional hacker, was hired by an organization to damage the reputation of their rival company. Williams spoofed a customer's rival company's IP address and initiated sending multiple ICMP ECHO request packets to an IP broadcast network. As a result, all the hosts together started sending responses to the customer's IP address. These responses were sent to the customer machine, diverting significant traffic toward it and crashing it in the process. Identify the type of attack performed by Williams in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "A. Fragmentation attack",
            "B. Smurf attack",
            "C. SYN flood attack",
            "D. Ping of death attack"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Smurf attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kevin, an attacker, is attempting to compromise a cloud server. In this process, Kevin intercepted the SOAP messages transmitted between a user and the server, manipulated the body of the message, and then redirected it to the server as a legitimate user to gain access and run malicious code on the cloud server. Identify the attack initiated by Kevin on the target cloud server.",
        "options": [
            "Side-channel attack",
            "Wrapping attack",
            "Cross guest VM breaches",
            "DNS spoofing"
        ],
        "answer": "Wrapping attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Roxanne is a professional hacker hired by an agency to disrupt the business services of their rival company. Roxanne employed a special type of malware that consumes a server's memory and network bandwidth when triggered. Consequently, the target server is overloaded and stops responding. Identify the type of malware Roxanne has used in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "Rootkit",
            "Armored virus",
            "worm",
            "Spyware"
        ],
        "answer": "worm"
    },
    {
        "question": "Melissa, an ex-employee of an organization, was fired because of misuse of resources and security violations. She sought revenge against the company and targeted its network, as she is already aware of its network topology. Which of the following categories of insiders does Melissa belong to?",
        "options": [
            "Malicious insider",
            "Professional insider",
            "Compromised insider",
            "Negligent insider"
        ],
        "answer": "Malicious insider"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following practices makes web applications vulnerable to SQL injection attacks?",
        "options": [
            "Use the most restrictive SQL account types for applications",
            "Never build Transact SQL statements directly from user input",
            "Avoid constructing dynamic SQL with concatenated input values",
            "A Accept entries that contain binary data, escape sequences, and comment characters"
        ],
        "answer": "A Accept entries that contain binary data, escape sequences, and comment characters"
    },
    {
        "question": "Melanie, a professional hacker, is attempting to break into a target network through an application server. In this process, she identified a logic flaw in the target web application that provided visibility into the source code. She exploited this vulnerability to launch further attacks on the target web application. Which of the web application vulnerabilities was identified by Melanie in the above scenario?",
        "options": [
            "Insecure deserialization",
            "Security misconfiguration",
            "Command injection",
            "Broken authentication"
        ],
        "answer": "Security misconfiguration"
    },
    {
        "question": "Johnson is a professional hacker who targeted an organization’s customers and decided to crack their system passwords. In this process, he found a list of valid customers, created a list of possible passwords, ranked the passwords from high to low probability, and started keying in each password in the target system until the correct password is discovered. Identify the type of attack performed by Johnson in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "Password guessing",
            "Rainbow table attack",
            "Dictionary attack",
            "Brute force attack"
        ],
        "answer": "Dictionary attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "William is an attacker who is attempting to hack Bluetooth-enabled devices at public places. Within the target’s range, he used special software to obtain the data stored in the victim’s device. He used a technique that exploits the vulnerability in the OBject Exchange (OBEX) protocol that Bluetooth uses to exchange information. Identify the attack performed by William in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "Bluesmacking",
            "Bluesnarfing",
            "Bluebugging",
            "Bluejacking"
        ],
        "answer": "Bluesnarfing"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following levels of the OSI model does an attacker gain control over the HTTP user session by obtaining the session IDs and create new unauthorized sessions by using the stolen data?",
        "options": [
            "Presentation level",
            "Transport level",
            "Network-level",
            "Application-level"
        ],
        "answer": "Application-level"
    },
    {
        "question": "Christian is working as a software developer in a reputed MNC. He received a message from XIM bank that claims to be urgent and requests to call a phone number mentioned in the message. Worried by this, he called the number to check on his account, believing it to be an authentic XIM Bank customer service phone number. A recorded message asks him to provide his credit or debit card number, as well as his password. Identify the type of social engineering attack being performed on Christian in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "SMiShing",
            "Spam mail",
            "Phishing",
            "Eavesdropping"
        ],
        "answer": "SMiShing"
    },
    {
        "question": "James is a professional hacker who managed to penetrate the target company’s network and tamper with software by adding a malicious script in the production that holds persistence on the network. Which of the following phases of hacking is James currently in?",
        "options": [
            "Clearing tracks",
            "Maintaining access",
            "Gaining access",
            "Scanning"
        ],
        "answer": "Maintaining access"
    },
    {
        "question": "Paola, a professional hacker, configured her wireless router in an organization's premises and advertised it with a spoofed SSID. She lured victims to connect to the router by sending the fake SSID. She started sniffing all the traffic from the victims that is passing through his wireless router. Which of the following types of attacks is Paola performing in the above scenario?",
        "options": [
            "Key reinstallation attack",
            "Ad-hoc connection attack",
            "Rogue AP attack",
            "AP MAC spoofing attack"
        ],
        "answer": "Rogue AP attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clark is an unskilled hacker attempting to perform an attack on a target organization to gain popularity. He downloaded and used freely available hacking tools and software developed by other professional hackers for this purpose. Identify the type of threat actor described in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "Script kiddie",
            "industrial spy",
            "Hacktivist",
            "Cyber terrorist"
        ],
        "answer": "Script kiddie"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cloud computing threats arises from authentication vulnerabilities, user-provisioning and de-provisioning vulnerabilities, hypervisor vulnerabilities, unclear roles and responsibilities, and misconfigurations?",
        "options": [
            "Supply-chain failure",
            "Isolation failure",
            "Subpoena and e discovery",
            "Privilege escalation"
        ],
        "answer": "Privilege escalation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Michael is an attacker who aims to hack Bob's system. He started collecting data without any active interaction with Bob's system. Using this technique. Michael can extract sensitive information from unencrypted data. Identify the class of attack Michael has launched in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "Ac live attack",
            "Insider attack",
            "Close in attack",
            "Passive attack"
        ],
        "answer": "Passive attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "James, a malware programmer, intruded into a manufacturing plant that produces computer peripheral devices. James tampered with the software inside devices ready to be delivered to clients. The tampered program creates a backdoor that allows unauthorized access to the systems. Identify the type of attack performed by James in the above scenario to gain unauthorized access to the delivered systems.",
        "options": [
            "Distribution Attack"
        ],
        "answer": "Distribution Attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given below are the various phases of hacking. 1. Reconnaissance 2. Gaining access 3. Maintaining access 4. Clearing tracks 5. Scanning What is the correct sequence of phases involved in hacking?",
        "options": [
            "A. 3 -> 1 -> 2 -> 5 -> 4",
            "B. 1 -> 2 -> 4 -> 5 -> 3",
            "C. 1 -> 5 -> 2 -> 3 -> 4",
            "D. 1 -> 2 -> 3 -> 4 -> 5"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 1 -> 5 -> 2 -> 3 -> 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given below are various stages involved in the virus lifecycle. 1. Replication 2. Incorporation 3. Launch 4. Execution of the damage routine 5. Design 6. Detection Identify the correct sequence of stages involved in the virus lifecycle.",
        "options": [
            "A. 3 -> 4 -> 5 -> 6 -> 1 -> 2",
            "B. 1 -> 2 -> 3 -> 4 -> 5 -> 6",
            "C. 5 -> 1 -> 3 -> 6 -> 2 -> 4",
            "D. 2 -> 3 -> 4 -> 1 -> 5 -> 6"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 5 -> 1 -> 3 -> 6 -> 2 -> 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "John, a professional hacker, targeted an employee of an organization to intrude and gain access to the corporate network. He employed a sniffer to capture packets and authentication tokens between the employee and the organization's server. After extracting relevant information, he transmitted the captured tokens back to the server to gain access as a legitimate user. Identify the type of attack performed by John in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "A. rainbow table attack",
            "B. brute-force attack",
            "C. LLMNR/NBTT-NS poisoning",
            "D. replay attack"
        ],
        "answer": "D. replay attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following practices can make devices or networks vulnerable to password cracking attempts?",
        "options": [
            "A. using different passwords that the time of password change",
            "B. not using a random string (salt) as a password prefix or suffix before performing encryption",
            "C. changing the system's default passwords",
            "D. using passwords that are not available in the dictionary"
        ],
        "answer": "B. not using a random string (salt) as a password prefix or suffix before performing encryption"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following types of identity theft does the perpetrator obtain information from different victims to create a new identity by stealing a social security number and use it with a combination of fake names, dates of birth, addresses, and other details required for creating a new identity?",
        "options": [
            "A. child identity theft",
            "B. synthetic identity theft",
            "C. social identity theft",
            "D. medical identity theft"
        ],
        "answer": "B. synthetic identity theft"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following protocols is used to communicate through port 23 and allows an attacker to log in to a network machine remotely via a TCP connection to sniff keystrokes, including usernames and passwords, that are sent in cleartext?",
        "options": [
            "A. NNTP",
            "B. POP",
            "C. HTTP",
            "D. Telnet"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Telnet"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following countermeasures helps security teams defend against sniffing attacks?",
        "options": [
            "A. use a hub instead of a switch",
            "B. always broadcast SSIDs",
            "C. use static IP addresses and ARP tables",
            "D. retrieve MAC addresses directly from OS instead of the NICs"
        ],
        "answer": "C. use static IP addresses and ARP tables"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following session hijacking phases does an attacker must change the sequence number or acknowledgment number (SEQ/ACK) of the server?",
        "options": [
            "A. command injection",
            "B. monitor",
            "C. session ID prediction",
            "D. session desynchronization"
        ],
        "answer": "D. session desynchronization"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ellie, an 18-year-old student, encrypts her drive with inbuilt Windows software so that her mischievous brother cannot access her assignments. Which software did Ellie use?",
        "options": [
            "Adobe",
            "Skype",
            "SPAMfighter",
            "BitLocker"
        ],
        "answer": "BitLocker"
    },
    {
        "question": "An attacker initiates a sniffing attack and gets sensitive data while in transition. What element of Information Security was affected?",
        "options": [
            "Availability",
            "Integrity",
            "Confidentiality",
            "Authenticity"
        ],
        "answer": "Confidentiality"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tampering with a server prior to installation is an example of what type of attack?",
        "options": [
            "Insider Attack",
            "Distribution Attack",
            "Brute-force Attack",
            "Denial-of-Service"
        ],
        "answer": "Distribution Attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "An attacker intercepted and monitored network traffic without tampering with the data. What type of attack is this?",
        "options": [
            "Active Attack",
            "Insider Attack",
            "Passive Attack",
            "Denial-of-Service"
        ],
        "answer": "Passive Attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'Electronic Transactions and Code Set Standards' are related to which civil act?",
        "options": [
            "SOX",
            "GLBA",
            "FISMA",
            "HIPAA"
        ],
        "answer": "HIPAA"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which phase of the Cyber Kill Chain methodology includes creating a deliverable payload?",
        "options": [
            "Reconnaissance",
            "Weaponization",
            "Delivery",
            "Exploitation"
        ],
        "answer": "Weaponization"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of hackers aims to bring down critical infrastructure for a 'cause' and isn't worried about facing jail terms or any other punishment?",
        "options": [
            "Black Hat Hackers",
            "Script Kiddies",
            "Suicide Hackers",
            "State-Sponsored Hackers"
        ],
        "answer": "Suicide Hackers"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term for an attacker who aims to gain popularity and uses existing tools to perform an attack?",
        "options": [
            "Ethical Hacker",
            "Script Kiddies",
            "Grey Hat Hacker",
            "Suicide Hacker"
        ],
        "answer": "Script Kiddies"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct order of the hacking phases?",
        "options": [
            "Reconnaissance, scanning, gaining access, maintaining access, clearing tracks",
            "Scanning, reconnaissance, gaining access, maintaining access, clearing tracks",
            "Gaining access, reconnaissance, scanning, maintaining access, clearing tracks",
            "Maintaining access, gaining access, reconnaissance, scanning, clearing tracks"
        ],
        "answer": "Reconnaissance, scanning, gaining access, maintaining access, clearing tracks"
    },
    {
        "question": "Using scripts to maintain persistence on a web server refers to which phase of the hacking phases?",
        "options": [
            "Scanning",
            "Gaining access",
            "Maintaining access",
            "Clearing tracks"
        ],
        "answer": "Maintaining access"
    },
    {
        "question": "An unskilled administrator who did not attend training claims to be an expert and makes configuration mistakes which lead to an attack. This is an example of what type of threat?",
        "options": [
            "Intentional Threats",
            "Unintentional Threats",
            "External Threats",
            "Environmental Threats"
        ],
        "answer": "Unintentional Threats"
    },
    {
        "question": "A shopping enthusiast receives an email to download a new shopping app, which leads to her data being accessed by an attacker. What is this an example of?",
        "options": [
            "Phishing",
            "Spear Phishing",
            "Rogue/Decoy Applications",
            "Vishing"
        ],
        "answer": "Rogue/Decoy Applications"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which component of a malware protects it from undergoing reverse engineering or analysis?",
        "options": [
            "Downloader",
            "Dropper",
            "Crypter",
            "Infector"
        ],
        "answer": "Crypter"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of malware is activated when a user performs certain predefined actions?",
        "options": [
            "Virus",
            "Worm",
            "Trojan",
            "Logic Bomb"
        ],
        "answer": "Trojan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of Trojan can destroy or change the entire content of a database or physically change the underlying HTML format of websites?",
        "options": [
            "Defacement Trojans",
            "Destructive Trojans",
            "Remote Access Trojans",
            "Proxy Trojans"
        ],
        "answer": "Defacement Trojans"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the sole purpose of a destructive Trojan?",
        "options": [
            "To steal data",
            "To delete files",
            "To record keystrokes",
            "To create a backdoor"
        ],
        "answer": "To delete files"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the stages of a virus lifecycle?",
        "options": [
            "Design, replication, launch, detection, incorporation, execution of the damage routine",
            "Replication, launch, detection, incorporation, execution of the damage routine",
            "Design, launch, replication, detection, incorporation, execution of the damage routine",
            "Replication, launch, detection, incorporation, execution"
        ],
        "answer": "Design, replication, launch, detection, incorporation, execution of the damage routine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of malware consumes network bandwidth, system memory, etc., excessively overloading servers and computer systems?",
        "options": [
            "Virus",
            "Worm",
            "Trojan",
            "Spyware"
        ],
        "answer": "Worm"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of password cracking attack involves creating a list of possible passwords, ranking them from high to low probability, and then entering each password until the correct one is discovered?",
        "options": [
            "Brute-force Attack",
            "Dictionary Attack",
            "Password Guessing",
            "Rainbow Table Attack"
        ],
        "answer": "Password Guessing"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Rainbow Table Attack is an example of which type of password cracking attack?",
        "options": [
            "Online Attacks",
            "Offline Attacks",
            "Dictionary Attacks",
            "Brute-force Attacks"
        ],
        "answer": "Offline Attacks"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a password cracking tool?",
        "options": [
            "Wireshark",
            "Nmap",
            "John the Ripper",
            "Metasploit"
        ],
        "answer": "John the Ripper"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a good countermeasure for password cracking?",
        "options": [
            "Use passwords that can be found in a dictionary",
            "Do not use passwords that can be found in a dictionary",
            "Use a single password for all accounts",
            "Do not change passwords frequently"
        ],
        "answer": "Do not use passwords that can be found in a dictionary"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term for the unauthorized listening to conversations or reading of messages, intercepting audio, video, or written communication?",
        "options": [
            "Spoofing",
            "Phishing",
            "Eavesdropping",
            "Social Engineering"
        ],
        "answer": "Eavesdropping"
    },
    {
        "question": "An attacker requests an authorized person to unlock a security door, saying they have forgotten their ID badge. What is this an example of?",
        "options": [
            "Tailgating",
            "Pretexting",
            "Piggybacking",
            "Baiting"
        ],
        "answer": "Piggybacking"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tracy, a software engineer, receives an SMS from what appears to be her bank. It asks her to call a listed number immediately. She calls, and a recorded message asks for her credit card number and password, which she provides. What is this attack called?",
        "options": [
            "Phishing",
            "Vishing",
            "SMiShing",
            "Pharming"
        ],
        "answer": "SMiShing"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term for a disgruntled or terminated employee who steals data or intentionally destroys a company's network by introducing malware?",
        "options": [
            "External Attacker",
            "Malicious Insider",
            "Script Kiddie",
            "State-Sponsored Hacker"
        ],
        "answer": "Malicious Insider"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of identity theft occurs when an attacker steals a Social Security Number and uses it with a combination of fake names, dates of birth, addresses, and other details to create a new identity?",
        "options": [
            "Financial Identity Theft",
            "Criminal Identity Theft",
            "Medical Identity Theft",
            "Synthetic Identity Theft"
        ],
        "answer": "Synthetic Identity Theft"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of attack makes a switch broadcast traffic to all connected devices?",
        "options": [
            "ARP Poisoning",
            "MAC Flooding",
            "DHCP Starvation",
            "Denial of Service"
        ],
        "answer": "MAC Flooding"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the process of inundating DHCP servers with fake DHCP requests, using all the available IP addresses?",
        "options": [
            "DHCP Spoofing",
            "DHCP starvation attack",
            "Man-in-the-Middle Attack",
            "ARP Spoofing"
        ],
        "answer": "DHCP starvation attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a sniffing countermeasure?",
        "options": [
            "Use dynamic IP addresses",
            "Use static IP addresses and ARP tables",
            "Disable firewalls",
            "Use unencrypted communication"
        ],
        "answer": "Use static IP addresses and ARP tables"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sniffer detection technique involves sending a non-broadcast ARP to all the nodes in the network?",
        "options": [
            "Ping Method",
            "ARP Method",
            "DNS Method",
            "Latency Method"
        ],
        "answer": "ARP Method"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of DDoS attack involves an attacker spoofing the source IP address with the victim's IP address and sending a large number of ICMP ECHO request packets to an IP broadcast network, causing all hosts to respond to the victim machine?",
        "options": [
            "SYN Flood",
            "UDP Flood",
            "Smurf DDoS Attack",
            "Ping of Death"
        ],
        "answer": "Smurf DDoS Attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of DDoS attack occurs when an attacker sends fraudulent content via email, IRC chats, tweets, or posts, which then gives the attacker access to the victim's computer?",
        "options": [
            "SYN Flood",
            "Permanent Denial-of-Service Attack",
            "HTTP Flood",
            "Smurf Attack"
        ],
        "answer": "Permanent Denial-of-Service Attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "What attack is also known as a brute-force attack, where an attacker makes several attempts to connect with varying session IDs until the actual session ID is determined, due to the absence of account lockout for invalid session IDs?",
        "options": [
            "Session fixation",
            "Session hijacking",
            "Brute-force attack",
            "Cross-Site Scripting"
        ],
        "answer": "Brute-force attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which phase of session hijacking must the attacker change the sequence number or acknowledgment number (SEQ/ACK) of the server?",
        "options": [
            "Packet sniffing",
            "Session desynchronization",
            "Session prediction",
            "Man-in-the-Middle"
        ],
        "answer": "Session desynchronization"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which component of a web server provides storage on a different machine or disk after the original disk becomes full and can be used to provide object-level security?",
        "options": [
            "Virtual Document Tree",
            "Virtual Hosting",
            "Web Server",
            "Web Proxy"
        ],
        "answer": "Virtual Document Tree"
    },
    {
        "question": "Using HTTP to perform an attack relates to the security of which layer of the OSI model?",
        "options": [
            "Network layer",
            "Data Link layer",
            "Transport layer",
            "Application layer"
        ],
        "answer": "Application layer"
    },
    {
        "question": "An attacker couldn't get access to internal resources due to a firewall, so he exploited a vulnerability in the web server to get to the internal resources. What type of attack did he perform?",
        "options": [
            "SQL Injection",
            "Cross-Site Scripting",
            "SSRF",
            "CSRF"
        ],
        "answer": "SSRF"
    },
    {
        "question": "A misconfiguration in the business flow relates to which layer of the web application architecture?",
        "options": [
            "Client-side logic layer",
            "web-server logic layer",
            "Database layer",
            "Backend API layer"
        ],
        "answer": "web-server logic layer"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following web application vulnerabilities allows untrusted data to be interpreted and executed as part of a command or query?",
        "options": [
            "Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)",
            "Injection flaws",
            "Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF)",
            "Broken Authentication"
        ],
        "answer": "Injection flaws"
    },
    {
        "question": "An attack case about sessions and their IDs relates to which type of vulnerability?",
        "options": [
            "Injection",
            "Broken Authentication",
            "Cross-Site Scripting",
            "Security Misconfiguration"
        ],
        "answer": "Broken Authentication"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of SQL injection involves an attacker injecting an additional malicious query into the original query?",
        "options": [
            "Piggybacked SQL injection",
            "Tautology-based SQL injection",
            "Union-based SQL injection",
            "Error-based SQL injection"
        ],
        "answer": "Piggybacked SQL injection"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a countermeasure for SQL injection attacks?",
        "options": [
            "Allow all data types in entries",
            "Reject entries that contain binary data, escape sequences, and comment characters",
            "Use dynamic queries",
            "Do not validate user input"
        ],
        "answer": "Reject entries that contain binary data, escape sequences, and comment characters"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of attack involves an attacker intercepting messages and resending them back to the server?",
        "options": [
            "Man-in-the-Middle Attack",
            "Replay attack",
            "Denial of Service",
            "Session Hijacking"
        ],
        "answer": "replay attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "A network administrator needs to connect 600 new laptops to a wireless network where the company has a single broadband router. What type of wireless network should he go for?",
        "options": [
            "Ad-hoc network",
            "Infrastructure network",
            "Extension to a Wired Network",
            "Wireless Mesh Network"
        ],
        "answer": "Extension to a Wired Network"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which IEEE 802 standard is related to WiMAX?",
        "options": [
            "802.11",
            "802.15",
            "802.16",
            "802.1X"
        ],
        "answer": "802.16"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the encryption algorithms used in WPA2?",
        "options": [
            "WEP",
            "TKIP",
            "AES-CCMP",
            "RC4"
        ],
        "answer": "AES-CCMP"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of wireless attack involves setting up an AP on a company's premises with a spoofed SSID?",
        "options": [
            "Eavesdropping",
            "Rogue AP Attack",
            "Deauthentication Attack",
            "Jamming"
        ],
        "answer": "Rogue AP Attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of wireless attack overwhelms the network with traffic?",
        "options": [
            "Deauthentication Attack",
            "Bluesnarfing",
            "Jamming",
            "Rogue AP Attack"
        ],
        "answer": "jamming"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of Bluetooth attacks exploits a vulnerability in the Object Exchange (OBEX) protocol?",
        "options": [
            "Bluejacking",
            "Bluesnarfing",
            "Bluebugging",
            "War-Driving"
        ],
        "answer": "Bluesnarfing"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the type of Bluetooth attack in which an attacker gains remote access to a target Bluetooth-enabled device and then uses that access for further attacks?",
        "options": [
            "Bluejacking",
            "Bluesnarfing",
            "Bluebugging",
            "War-Driving"
        ],
        "answer": "Bluebugging"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following mobile threats/attacks helps attackers gain access and retrieve sensitive data?",
        "options": [
            "Code Tampering",
            "Cryptographic Vulnerabilities",
            "Client Code Quality",
            "Side-Channel Attacks"
        ],
        "answer": "Client Code Quality"
    },
    {
        "question": "What category of mobile threat/attack refers to binary patching, local resource modification, method hooking, method swizzling, and dynamic memory modification?",
        "options": [
            "Malicious Applications",
            "Code Tampering",
            "Insecure Data Storage",
            "Side-Channel Attacks"
        ],
        "answer": "Code Tampering"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of an attack that is carried out by persuading the victim to install a malicious app designed and published by an attacker?",
        "options": [
            "Agent Smith Attack",
            "Pegasus Attack",
            "Stagefright Attack",
            "Smsjacking"
        ],
        "answer": "Agent smith attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "An employee working remotely used her laptop in a cafe to check her work email using the cafe's network. What risk is related to this scenario?",
        "options": [
            "Using insecure channels",
            "Physical theft of the device",
            "Shoulder surfing",
            "Malicious insider"
        ],
        "answer": "using insecure channels"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a general guideline for mobile platform security?",
        "options": [
            "Use untrusted third-party app stores",
            "Maintain configuration control and management",
            "Do not use device encryption",
            "Disable screen lock"
        ],
        "answer": "Maintain configuration control and management"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which IoT architecture layer is responsible for the sensors and hardware?",
        "options": [
            "Edge Technology Layer",
            "Data Aggregation Layer",
            "Application Layer",
            "Device Layer"
        ],
        "answer": "Edge Technology Layer"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which IoT architecture layer is responsible for the delivery of services to the relevant users from different sectors?",
        "options": [
            "Application Layer",
            "Data Aggregation Layer",
            "Edge Technology Layer",
            "Device Layer"
        ],
        "answer": "Application Layer"
    },
    {
        "question": "IoT security problems such as insecure API, lack of communication channels encryption, authentication, and lack of storage security relate to which layer?",
        "options": [
            "Cloud",
            "Gateway",
            "Mobile",
            "API"
        ],
        "answer": "Mobile"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the IoT attacks refers to attackers intercepting legitimate messages from valid communication and continuously sending the intercepted message to the target device to perform a denial-of-service attack?",
        "options": [
            "Replay Attack",
            "Man-in-the-Middle",
            "Physical Attack",
            "Jamming"
        ],
        "answer": "Replay Attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of attack involves attackers tampering with the operating conditions, modifying the level of the power supply, and/or altering the clock frequency of the chip?",
        "options": [
            "Frequency/Voltage Tampering",
            "Physical Attack",
            "Software Attack",
            "Jamming"
        ],
        "answer": "Frequency/Voltage Tampering"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an IoT attack countermeasure?",
        "options": [
            "Enable telnet (port 23)",
            "Use default passwords",
            "Disable telnet (port 23)",
            "Do not update firmware"
        ],
        "answer": "Disable telnet (port 23)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What technique is used to isolate networks and assets to impose and maintain strong access control mechanisms?",
        "options": [
            "Demilitarized Zone (DMZ)",
            "Firewall",
            "Zones and Conduits",
            "VLAN"
        ],
        "answer": "Zones and Conduits"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of attack involves attackers retrieving critical information from an OT system by observing its physical implementation using techniques like timing analysis and power analysis?",
        "options": [
            "Side-Channel Attacks",
            "Physical Attacks",
            "DDoS Attacks",
            "Logic Attacks"
        ],
        "answer": "Side-Channel Attacks"
    },
    {
        "question": "What attack involves attackers hijacking the original remote controller and pairing it with the machine using a malicious RF controller disguised as a legitimate one?",
        "options": [
            "Re-pairing with Malicious RF controller",
            "Signal Jamming",
            "Man-in-the-Middle Attack",
            "Eavesdropping"
        ],
        "answer": "Re-pairing with Malicious RF controller"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud service model offers development tools, configuration management, and deployment platforms on-demand that can be used by subscribers to develop custom applications?",
        "options": [
            "IaaS",
            "SaaS",
            "PaaS",
            "FaaS"
        ],
        "answer": "PaaS"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of cloud deployment model allows an organization to retain full control over its corporate data?",
        "options": [
            "Public Cloud",
            "Private Cloud",
            "Hybrid Cloud",
            "Community Cloud"
        ],
        "answer": "Private Cloud"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the NIST framework, which cloud entity manages cloud services in terms of use, performance, and delivery, and maintains the relationship between cloud providers and consumers?",
        "options": [
            "Cloud Carrier",
            "Cloud Broker",
            "Cloud Provider",
            "Cloud Auditor"
        ],
        "answer": "Cloud Broker"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tier of container technology is responsible for storing images and disseminating images to the orchestrators based on requests?",
        "options": [
            "Orchestration",
            "Runtime",
            "Registries",
            "Hosting"
        ],
        "answer": "Registries"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term for a type of cloud attack where one cloud customer can access the data or resources of another customer, often due to misconfiguration of the cloud environment?",
        "options": [
            "Isolation Failure",
            "Data Breach",
            "Denial of Service",
            "Man-in-the-Middle Attack"
        ],
        "answer": "Isolation Failure"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of attack is performed during the translation of the SOAP message in the TLS layer, where attackers duplicate the body of the message and send it to the server as a legitimate user?",
        "options": [
            "Man-in-the-Middle Attack",
            "Replay Attack",
            "Wrapping attack",
            "Spoofing"
        ],
        "answer": "Wrapping attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "A user receives a fitness report that looks unusual and is asked for credentials. What type of attack is this, related to cloud storage?",
        "options": [
            "Phishing",
            "Cloud storage attack",
            "Social Engineering",
            "Man-in-the-Middle Attack"
        ],
        "answer": "cloud storage"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the goal of a penetration test is defined before it begins as risk assessment, what type of penetration test is it?",
        "options": [
            "Compliance-oriented penetration test",
            "Red-team-oriented penetration test",
            "Goal-oriented penetration test",
            "External penetration test"
        ],
        "answer": "Goal-oriented pentation test"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of penetration test assesses against the compliance requirements of cybersecurity standards, frameworks, laws, and acts?",
        "options": [
            "Compliance-oriented penetration test",
            "Goal-oriented penetration test",
            "Red-team-oriented penetration test",
            "Internal penetration test"
        ],
        "answer": "Compliance-oriented pentation test"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of penetration test mimics the behavior of a real attacker to evaluate the overall security of an organization?",
        "options": [
            "Goal-oriented penetration test",
            "Red-team-oriented penetration test",
            "Compliance-oriented penetration test",
            "Vulnerability assessment"
        ],
        "answer": "Red-team-oriented pentation test"
    },
    {
        "question": "Don, a professional hacker, targeted an organization and decided to disrupt its online services. Don initiated an attack by injecting a malicious query into the original query Which of the following types attack has Don performed in the above scenario?",
        "options": [
            "A. tautology",
            "B. piggybacked query",
            "C. logical incorrect query",
            "D. illegal incorrect query"
        ],
        "answer": "B. piggybacked query"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following practices can make an application or database server vulnerable to SQL injection attacks?",
        "options": [
            "A. test the content of string variables and accept only expected values",
            "B. keep untrusted data separate from commands and queries",
            "C. allow entries that contain binary data, escape sequences, and comment characters",
            "D. apply least privilege rules to run the applications that access the DBMS"
        ],
        "answer": "C. allow entries that contain binary data, escape sequences, and comment characters"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following defines the standards for a WiMax and designed to provide multiple physical layer (PHY) and MAC options?",
        "options": [
            "A. 802.12",
            "B. 802.11i",
            "C. 802.16",
            "D. 802.15.4"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 802.16"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following types of attack involves replacing legitimate apps in a mobile device with malicious apps designed by a hacker and producing a large volume of advertisements on the target device to attain financial benefits?",
        "options": [
            "A. SIM card attack",
            "B. SMiShing attack",
            "C. Bluesnarfing attack",
            "D. Agent smith attack"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Agent smith attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alana, an employee in an organization, took a short break after spending exhausting hours on a project. For relaxation, she went to a cafeteria with her laptop, where she connected to the public Internet. While browsing the web, she received a project modifications file on her mail and reverted with another file that contained the required changes. Which of the following BYOD risk was demonstrated in the above scenario?",
        "options": [
            "A. improperly disposing of devices",
            "B. disgruntled employees",
            "C. sharing confidential data on unsecured networks",
            "D. infrastructure issues"
        ],
        "answer": "C. sharing confidential data on unsecured networks"
    },
    {
        "question": "Joseph, a professional hacker, targeted an employee of an organization to intrude and gain access to the network. He initiated the attack using sniffers to capture packets and authentication tokens between the employee and the server he was communicating with. After intercepting the messages, he started continuously sending the intercepted messages to the server. Identify the type of attack performed by Joseph in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "A. replay attack",
            "B. dictionary attack",
            "C. rainbow table attack",
            "D. brute-force attack"
        ],
        "answer": "A. replay attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following countermeasures helps security professionals in securing an IoT device from malicious activity?",
        "options": [
            "A. enable UPnP port on routers",
            "B. disable monitor traffic on port 48101",
            "C. disable telnet (port 23)",
            "D. enable \"guest\" and \"demo\" user accounts"
        ],
        "answer": "C. disable telnet (port 23)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the attack in which attackers use timing analysis and power analysis techniques to retrieve critical information from an OT system.",
        "options": [
            "A. malware attack",
            "B. spear phishing",
            "C. side-channel attack",
            "D. buffer overflow attack"
        ],
        "answer": "C. side-channel attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Jane, a third-party security auditor, received an email from one of his client organizations seeking advice on securing corporate data on the cloud environment. Jane suggested a cloud deployment model that provides full control over corporate data and can be managed within the organization. Which of the following cloud deployment models has Jane suggested to the organization?",
        "options": [
            "A. public cloud",
            "B. private cloud",
            "C. community cloud",
            "D. multi cloud"
        ],
        "answer": "B. private cloud"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the NIST cloud deployment reference architecture entity that manages cloud services regarding use, performance, and delivery and maintains the relationship between CSPs and cloud consumers.",
        "options": [
            "A. cloud provider",
            "B. cloud carrier",
            "C. cloud auditor",
            "D. cloud broker"
        ],
        "answer": "D. cloud broker"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following components in Docker architecture refers to locations where images are stored and pulled whenever required?",
        "options": [
            "A. Docker Objects",
            "B. Docker Registries",
            "C. Docker Daemon",
            "D. Docker Client"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Docker Registries"
    },
    {
        "question": "Irin, a cloud security architect, is a disgruntled ex-employee of an organization who has access to cloud resources and knows about the organization's cloud network. Using this information, she deliberately accesses the critical documents and compromises the sensitive information available in the cloud. Identify the cloud threat demonstrated in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "A. supply chain failure",
            "B. cloud provider acquisition",
            "C. malicious insiders",
            "D. isolation failure"
        ],
        "answer": "C. malicious insiders"
    },
    {
        "question": "James, a certified hacker, was hired to intrude into an organization's network to perform malicious activities. James targeted an employee's system and started sending fraudulent and defective firmware updates. Soon after the employee clicked on one of the updates received, the attacker achieved complete control over the victim's system and gained access to the organization's network. Identity the type of attack performed by James in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "Permanent Denial of Service Attack"
        ],
        "answer": "Permanent Denial of Service Attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "John, a professional penetration tester, was hired by an organization for conducting a penetration test on their IT infrastructure. He was assigned the task of identifying risks, rather than finding vulnerabilities. In this process, he defined the goal before initiating the penetration test and performed multiple parallel processes to achieve the goal. Identify the type of penetration testing approach followed by John in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "A. goal-oriented penetration testing approach",
            "B. compliance-oriented penetration testing approach",
            "C. objective-oriented penetration testing approach",
            "D. red-team-oriented penetration testing approach"
        ],
        "answer": "A. goal-oriented penetration testing approach"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following malware components protects malware from reverse engineering or analysis, thus making it difficult to detect by security mechanisms?",
        "options": [
            "A. dropper",
            "B. payload",
            "C. downloader",
            "D. crypter"
        ],
        "answer": "D. crypter"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following encryption algorithms does WPK2 use?",
        "options": [
            "A. AES - CCMP",
            "B. AES-GCMP",
            "C. RSA",
            "D. RC4"
        ],
        "answer": "A. AES - CCMP"
    },
    {
        "question": "Abel, a cloud architect, uses container technology to deploy applications/software including all its dependencies, such as libraries and configuration files, binaries, and other resources that run independently from other processes in the cloud environment. For the containerization of applications, he follows the five-tier container technology architecture. Currently, Abel is storing images and disseminating images to the orchestrators based on requests. Which of the following tiers of the container technology architecture is Abel currently working in?",
        "options": [
            "A. Tier-1: Developer machines",
            "B. Tier-2: Testing and accreditation systems",
            "C. Tier-3: Registries",
            "D. Tier-4: Orchestrators"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Tier-3: Registries"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which IoT architecture faces these security issues Insecure API, lack of communication channels encryption, authentication, lack of storage security?",
        "options": [
            "Mobile"
        ],
        "answer": "Mobile"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following tools is used for Password Cracking?",
        "options": [
            "John the Ripper"
        ],
        "answer": "John the Ripper"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the network segregation technique that is used to isolate networks and assets to impose and maintain strong access control mechanisms.",
        "options": [
            "Zones and Conduits"
        ],
        "answer": "Zones and Conduits"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is defined as storage on a different machine or disk after the original disk becomes full, is case-sensitive, and can be used to provide object-level security?",
        "options": [
            "A) Virtual Document Tree",
            "B) Cloud Storage Gateway",
            "C) Distributed Database",
            "D) Directory Service"
        ],
        "answer": "A) Virtual Document Tree"
    },
    {
        "question": "Daniel, a professional hacker, targeted Alice and lured her into downloading a malicious app from a third-party app store. Upon installation, the core malicious code inside the application started infecting other legitimate apps in Alice's mobile device. Daniel overloaded Alice's device with irrelevant and fraudulent advertisements through the infected app for financial gain. Identify the type of attack Daniel has launched in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "Agent Smith attack"
        ],
        "answer": "Agent Smith attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Robert, a security specialist, was appointed to strengthen the security of the organization's network. To prevent multiple login attempts from unknown sources, Robert implemented a security strategy of issuing alerts or warning messages when multiple failed login attempts are made. Which of the following security risks is addressed by Robert to make attempted break-ins unsuccessful?",
        "options": [
            "Absence of account lockout for invalid session IDs"
        ],
        "answer": "Absence of account lockout for invalid session IDs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wesley, a fitness freak, purchased a new Apple smartwatch and synced it with a mobile app downloaded from an unauthorized third party. At the end of the day, when Wesley attempted to access his fitness report from the app, it generated an unusual report and asked for some unnecessary permissions to view it. Which of the following mobile risks is demonstrated in the above scenario?",
        "options": [
            "Improper platform usage"
        ],
        "answer": "Improper platform usage"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bruce, a professional hacker, targeted an OT network. He initiated a looping strategy to recover the password of the target system. He started sending one character at a time to check whether the first character entered is correct: If so, he continued the loop for consecutive characters. Using thistechnique. Bruce identified how much time the device takes to finish one complete password authentication process, through which he determined the correct characters in the target password. Identify the type of attack launched by Bruce on the target OT network.",
        "options": [
            "side-channel attack"
        ],
        "answer": "side-channel attack"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cibel.org, an organization, wanted to develop a web application for marketing its products to the public. In this process, they consulted a cloud service provider and requested provision of development tools, configuration management, and deployment platforms for developing customized applications. Identify the type of cloud service requested by Cibel.org in the above scenario.",
        "options": [
            "Platform-as-a-service"
        ],
        "answer": "Platform-as-a-service"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is defined as individuals who aim to bring down critical infrastructure for a “cause” and are unconcerned about facing jail terms or other punishment?",
        "options": [
            "A) Suicide Hackers",
            "B) Script Kiddies",
            "C) Insider Threats",
            "D) Hacktivists"
        ],
        "answer": "A) Suicide Hackers"
    }
]
